Register of the A. (Andrei) Siniavskii Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1940's-1998
  - Public lectures., See also OVERSIZE FILE/Posters/Public appearances of Andrei Siniavskii and Mariia Rozanova
    - "Zhitie Protopopa Avvakuma," Columbia University, 1978 (Folder 46: 13)
    - "Pouchkine le poète russe," readings sponsored by France Culture, 1983 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - "The Literary Masks of Aleksei Remizov," review of talk delivered at Dartmouth Colege, 1985 (Folder 47: 2)
    - Dialog with professors and students at the Literaturnyi institut imeni Gor'kogo, Irkutsk, 1992. (Folder 47: 3)
    - Questions from the audience, meeting in the public library, Syzran', Russia, 1994. (Folder 47: 4)
      Handwritten
    - Untitled lecture, Congresso Internazionale, Genoa, Italy, 1995. (Folder 47: 5)
  - Radio program transcripts., See also AUDIO-VISUAL FILE/Phonotapes/Siniavskii, Andrei
    Typescripts, arranged by radio station and therein by title.
    - BBC, Russian Service. Program entitled "Povorot vinta," lecture entitled "Intelligentsiia i khleb," 1996 (Folder 47: 6)
    - Radio Liberty
      - "Dnevnik pisatelia," re Protopop Avvakum, n.d. (Folder 47: 7)
      - "My za granitsei"
        - Nos. 6, 7, 9 (Folder 47: 8)
        - Nos. 14, 18, 19 (Folder 47: 9)
        - Nos. 20-23 (Folder 47: 10)
        - Nos. 26-28 (Folder 47: 11)
        - Nos. 44, 50, 78 (Folder 47: 12)
      - "Obzor kul'turnoi zhizni," re Boris Pasternak, 1975. (Folder 47: 13)
      - "Pasternak," 1985. (Folder 47: 14)
      - "Spokoinoi nochi: Roman s kommentariiami." Read by Andrei Siniavskii with commentary by Mariia Rozanova, 1985., See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Creative writing under the pseudonym of Abram Terts/Spokoinoi nochi (Folder 47: 15)
        Typescript draft.
        - Nos. 1-10 (Folder 47: 16)
        - Nos. 11-20 (Folder 47: 17)
        - Nos. 21-30 (Folder 47: 18)
      - "Velimir Khlebnikov," 1985. (Folder 47: 19)
    - Recommendation, 1991. (Folder 47: 20)
  - Scholarly work by title, arranged chronologically. (Box 48)
    Holograph drafts unless otherwise indicated
    - General
      - List of writings, 1959-1964. (Folder 48: 1)
      - Short and untitled writings, n.d. (Folder 48: 2-3)
    - Untitled notes on Italy, n.d. (Folder 48: 4)
    - "Davaite govorit' professional'no: Otvet nekotorym poetam i kritikam" (with A. Menshutin for Novyi mir), n.d. (Folder 48: 5)
    - "Dissidentskie nabroski," n.d. (Folder 48: 6)
    - "Dostoevskii i XX vek," n.d. (Folder 48: 7)
    - "Dostoevskii i Rozanov," n.d. (Folder 48: 8)
    - Entries for Elena Guro, Nikolai Kliuev, Konstruktivizm, and Mikhail Kuzmin, Bol'shaia sovetskaia entsyklopediia, n.d. (Folder 48: 9)
    - "Igra so spichkami," n.d. (Folder 48: 10)
      Typescript draft with handwritten corrections
    - "Iskusstvo v totalitarnom mire," n.d. (Folder 48: 11)
    - "Ivan-Durak: Ocherk russkoi narodnoi very," n.d.
      - Working papers (Folder 48: 12-13)
      - Holograph draft (Box 49)
        - "Vstuplenie" (Folder 49: 1)
        - "Chast' pervaia" (Folder 49: 2-5)
        - "Chast' chetvertaia" (Folder 49: 6-8)
        - "Vmesto zakliucheniia" (Folder 49: 9)
      - Typeset with handwritten corrections, n.d. (Folder 49: 10-12)
      - Reviews of French edition, Ivan le simple: Paganisme, magie et religion du peuple russe, 1990-1991 (Folder 49: 13)
    - "Mify Mikhaila Zoshchenko," n.d. (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - "Neskol'ko slov (po pravu otveta) o Vestnike Nos. 142," n.d. (Folder 50: 2)
    - "Noch' posle bitvy," handwritten, n.d. (Folder 50: 3)
    - "O tsenzure," n.d. (Folder 50: 4)
    - Osnovy sovetskoi tsivilizatsii, n.d.
      - Page proofs with handwritten corrections, n.d.
        - Chapters 1-3 (Folder 50: 5)
        - Chapters 4-5 (Folder 50: 6)
        - Chapters 6-8 (Folder 50: 7)
      - Reviews
        - English edition, Soviet Civilization: A Cultural History, 1990-1991 (Folder 50: 8)
        - French edition, La civilisation soviétique, 1989 (Folder 50: 9)
    - "Otvety na voprosy ankety," n.d. (Folder 50: 10)
    - "'Panorama s vynoskami' Mikhaila Kuzmina," n.d. (Folder 50: 11)
    - "Poezdka v Moskvu," n.d. (Folder 50: 12)
    - "Poeziia 1908-1917 godov," n.d. (Folder 50: 13)
    - "Romantika boev i pokhodov," chapter 3 of unidentified work, n.d. (Folder 50: 14)
    - "Russkaia literatura i krizis sovetskogo obshchestva," n.d. (Folder 50: 15)
    - "Russkaia literatura XX veka." Preparatory material, n.d. (Box-folder 51: 1-5)
    - "Russkaia poeziia XX veka," n.d.
      - Introduction (Folder 51: 6)
      - Chapter 1 (Folder 51: 7)
      - Chapter 2 (Box-folder 52: 1-2)
    - "Russkii futurizm," n.d. (Folder 52: 3)
    - "Zemlia i nebo v isskusstve drevnei Rusi," n.d. (Folder 52: 4)
      Chapters for projected book with Mariia Rozanova. Typescript
    - "Socialist Realism," Soviet Survey, 1959 July-September. (Folder 52: 5)
    - "Pamflet ili paskvil'?" 1964. (Folder 52: 6)
      Review of Ivan Shevtsov, Tlia: Roman-pamflet. Typescript
    - "Poidem so mnoi," 1964. (Folder 52: 7)
      Review of Robert Frost: Iz deviati knig: Perevod s angliiskogo pod redaktsiei i s predisloviem M. A. Zenkevicha. Typescript
    - "Est' takie stikhi...," 1965. (Folder 52: 8)
      Review of Evgenii Dolmatovskii, Stikhi o nas. Typescript
    - "Tochka otshcheta," 1965. (Folder 52: 9)
      Manuscript confiscated at the time of the author's arrest
    - "V zashchitu Piramidy," 1965.
      Article prepared for publication in Novyi Mir at the time of the author's arrest
      - Holograph (Folder 52: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 52: 11)
    - "La voix délivrée de ses chaînes," Preuves, 1966 January. (Folder 52: 12)
    - "On Evtushenko," Encounter, 1967. (Folder 52: 13)
    - "In Defense of Pyramids," Problems of Communism, 1968 September-October. (Folder 52: 14)
    - "Literaturnyi protses v Rossii," 1974. (Folder 52: 15)
    - "Father Boris Zalivako," Religion in Communist Lands, 1974 May-June. (Folder 52: 16)
    - "Émigré," Encounter, 1978 September. (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - "La France de Andrei Siniavski," Le nouvel observateur, 1980 (Folder 53: 2)
    - "Sny na pravoslavnuiu Paskhu," 1980 (Folder 53: 3)
    - "Le regard du bagnard," 1981. (Folder 53: 4)
      Clipping
    - "Dissent as a Personal Experience," Dissent, 1984 Spring (Folder 53: 5)
    - La dissidence comme expérience personnelle, 1984. (Folder 53: 6)
    - Letters to the editor, Russkaia Mysl', 1984 February (Folder 53: 7)
    - "Dissidentstvo kak lichnyi opyt," 1986. On reverse side, "Spokoinoi nochi," 1984 (Folder 53: 8)
    - "Pochemu byl unichtozhen Anatolii Marchenko?," 1986. (Folder 53: 9)
      Holograph draft and typescript
    - "Izraztsy," 1987. (Folder 53: 10)
    - "L'espace de la prose," La nouvelle alternative, 1988. (Folder 53: 11)
    - "A Trip to Moscow," Index on Censorship, 1989 December. (Folder 53: 12)
    - "Russophobia," Partisan Review, 1990. (Folder 53: 13)
    - "Solzhenitsyn kak ustroitel' novogo edinomysliia," Protivostoianie, St. Petersburg, 1990. (Folder 53: 14)
    - Untitled, published in Granta, 1990 (Folder 53: 15)
    - Review of The Russian Intelligentsia in The New York Review of Books, 1998 April (Folder 53: 16)
    - "Worse Than Communists," New York Times Op-Ed, 1996 (Folder 53: 17)
  - Scholarly work by subject, arranged alphabetically
    - General. Notes and research material on miscellaneous literary and political subjects, 1943-1965?
      - 19th century (Folder 53: 18-20)
      - 19th century (Box-folder 54: 1-4)
      - 20th century (Folder 54: 5-9)
      - 20th century (Box-folder 55: 1-2)
    - Babel', Isaak
      - General
        - Copies of texts
          - Correspondence, 1923-1931. (Folder 55: 3)
          - Newspaper articles under the signature of K. Liutov, 1924. (Folder 55: 4)
          - Short stories, 1923-1928. (Folder 55: 5)
        - Notes and miscellany (Folder 55: 6)
      - "Babel'," lecture, n.d. (Folder 55: 7)
      - "I. E. Babel'," n.d.
        - Holograph (Folder 55: 8)
        - Typescript (Folder 55: 9)
      - "Na puti k Konarmii(Literaturnye iskaniia Babelia)." Article with I. Smirin for I. Babel': Novye materialy, 1963-1964
        - Holograph (Folder 55: 10)
        - Galley proof (Folder 55: 11)
    - Bagritskii, Eduard
      - "E. Bagritskii: Risunki poeta," n.d.
        - Typescript (Folder 55: 12)
        - Galley proof (Folder 55: 13)
      - "E. Bagritskii," 1958. (Folder 55: 14)
    - Gogol', Nikolai, "Vzaimodeistvie i sootnoshenie romanticheskogo i realisticheskogo kak stilevykh kategorii slovesnogo iskusstva 'Arabesok' Gogolia," n.d. (Box-folder 56: 1)
    - Gor'kii, Maksim
      - General - Research material
        - Clipping of obituary in Sovetskoe Iskusstvo, 1936 (Folder 56: 2)
        - Notebooks, n.d.
          - General (Folder 56: 3-7)
          - Nos. 1-2 (Folder 56: 8)
          - Nos. 3-4 (Folder 56: 9)
          - Nos. 5-6 (Folder 56: 10)
      - "Tema intelligentsii v dramaturgii M. Gor'kogo 1901-1906 gg.," n.d. (Folder 56: 11)
        Graduate school paper. Typescript
      - Roman M. Gor'kogo 'Zhizn' Klima Samgina' I istoriia russkoi obshchestvennoi mysli kontsa XIX - nachala XX veka. Dissertation submitted to Moscow University for the degree of 'candidat filologicheskikh nauk', 1952
        - Printed copy (Folder 56: 12)
        - Readers' evaluations by Boris Mikhailovskii and E. Tager. (Folder 56: 13)
    - Khlebnikov, Velemir, "Poslerevoliutsionnye poemy Khlebnikova," 1946. (Box-folder 57: 1)
      Notebooks
    - Klychkov, Sergei, n.d., See also PHOTOGRAPHS (Folder 57: 2-4)
      Notes and copies of work by and about Klychkov, 1929-1989. Typescript and printed matter.
    - Maiakovskii, Vladimir
      - Draft of proposed book entitled Novoe o Maiakovskom, n.d. (Folder 57: 5-6)
        Typescript, galley-proofs, and clippings. Also includes letter to the Harriman Institute, 1985, and draft of an article by Andrei Siniavskii entitled "Perepiska s El'zoi Triole," 1987, prepared for proposed publisher, Bentt Jangdfeldt
      - Miscellaneous short writings. (Folder 57: 7)
      - Obituaries. Clippings from Soviet press, 1930 (Folder 57: 8)
      - Program., See OVERSIZE FILE/Posters
      - Research material. (Folder 57: 9-12)
        Typescript copies of writings, correspondence, and memoirs about Maiakovskii
    - Malraux, André. Translation, "Metamorfozy Apollona," n.d. (Folder 57: 13)
    - Pasternak, Boris (Box 58)
      - General. Notes and photocopies of texts. (Folder 58: 1-3)
        Includes "Stenograma obshchemoskovskogo sobraniia pisatelei 31 oktiabria 1958 goda," 1958. Typescript
      - "Boris Pasternak," draft of article for Kritisches Lexikon zur deutschsprachigen Gegenwartsliteratur. (Folder 58: 4)
      - "Gamlet u Pasternaka," article, n.d. (Folder 58: 5)
      - "Poeziia Pasternaka," draft of article for Prof. Victor Ehrlich, n.d. (Folder 58: 6)
      - "Pokhorony Pasternaka," reminiscences, n.d. (Folder 58: 7)
      - Review of Boris Pasternak: Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, Goslitizdat, 1961. (Folder 58: 8)
      - "Poeziia Pasternaka," introduction to Boris Pasternak: Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, Sovetskii Pisatel', Leningrad, 1965
        - Typescript draft with handwritten corrections (Folder 58: 9)
        - Commentary by Evgenii Pasternak on Andrei Siniavskii's introduction, n.d. (Folder 58: 10)
        - Correspondence with publisher, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1962-1965. (Folder 58: 11)
          Includes correspondence of B. Egorov, E. Pasternak, and G. Tsurikova
        - Reviews - Ginsburg, L., 1963. (Folder 58: 12)
      - "On Boris Pasternak," Encounter, 1966 April. (Folder 58: 13)
      - Comments by Andrei Siniavskii at Serizy Conference, 1975. (Folder 58: 14)
    - Rozanov, Vasilii. Preparatory material and draft of "Opavshie list'ia V. V. Rozanova," n.d. (Folder 58: 15)
- DONAT SINIAVSKII FILE, 1914-1960 (Box 59)
  - Biographical file
    - Application for scientific patent, n.d. (Folder 59: 1)
    - Marriage certificate of Donat Siniavskii and Evdokiia Torkhova, 1914 (Folder 59: 2)
    - Identification documents, 1919, 1935 (Folder 59: 3)
    - Papers related to the Siniavskii house in the village of Rameno, Russia, 1927-1932 (Folder 59: 4)
    - Application for membership in the Communist Party, 1928-1930. (Folder 59: 5)
      Photocopy from dossier in Gosudarstvennyi Arkhiv Rossiiskoi Federatsii. Includes his political autobiography
    - Records of interrogations after his arrest by the KGB, 1950-1951. (Folder 59: 6)
      Photocopies of typescript and handwritten material from the Tsentral'nyi Arkhiv FSB RF
    - Protocols re property confiscated by the KGB, 1950-1951. (Folder 59: 7)
      Handwritten and typescript
    - Response to request for biographical information from Serovskii Kraevedcheskii Muzei, 1955. (Folder 59: 8)
    - Notice of rehabilitation by the Supreme Court of the U.S.S.R., 1956 (Folder 59: 9)
    - Death certificate, 1960 (Folder 59: 10)
  - Correspondence with Andrei Siniavskii and Siniavskii family, 1953-1958 (Folder 59: 11)
  - Printed matter
    - Booklets used in village education campaign, n.d. (Folder 59: 12)
      Includes K. Altaiskii, Rasskaz ob agronome Litvinenko, and Irina Lazareva, Kak oni goriat
    - Journal. Novyi zritel', No. 3, 1928 (Folder 59: 13)
    - Leaflet. Announcement for village theater, n.d. (Folder 59: 14)
  - Writings. Some under pseudonym of S. Dondau
    - Newspaper articles, 1920's (Folder 59: 15)
    - Plays
      - General
        - Lecture, "Osnovnoi tezis doklada o teatre," 1919. (Folder 59: 16)
        - Stage directions, "Detalirovka k postanovke 'Ot velikogo do smeshnogo odin shag," n.d. (Folder 59: 17)
      - Chas raven godu, n.d. (Folder 59: 18)
      - "Phonar' Diogena," n.d. (Folder 59: 19)
      - "Prezhde i teper'," n.d. (Folder 59: 20)
      - "Ryzhii bekas," n.d. (Folder 59: 21)
      - "Son v politicheskuiu maslenitsu," 1917. (Folder 59: 22)
      - "Zverinets," 1923-1925. (Folder 59: 23-24)
      - "Konets Romanovykh," 1927. (Folder 59: 25-26)
      - "Podlets: Tainy morali," 1937. (Folder 59: 27)
      - "Bessmertie: Legenda i zhizn'," 1945. (Folder 59: 28)
    - Poetry, n.d. (Folder 59: 29)
    - Prose and scientific texts (Box 60)
      - General, n.d. (Folder 60: 1)
      - Untitled, n.d. (Folder 60: 2)
      - "Chapany," n.d. (Folder 60: 3-5)
      - "Chem sil'na zhizn'," n.d. (Folder 60: 6)
      - "Doroga smerti," n.d. (Folder 60: 7)
      - "Homo sapiens," n.d. (Folder 60: 8)
      - "Povsednevnoe," n.d. (Folder 60: 9)
      - "Pravo na zhizn'," n.d. (Folder 60: 10)
      - "V detskoi bol'nitse," n.d. (Folder 60: 11)
      - Proiskhozhdenie zhizni, 1924. (Folder 60: 12)
      - Razvitie mozga, razvitie razuma, 1924. (Folder 60: 13)
      - Razvitie pozvonochnykh vodnykh i zemnovodnykh, 1924. (Folder 60: 14)
      - Zakony izmeniaemosti zhivotnykh, 1924. (Folder 60: 15)
      - "Na perepakhannoi doroge," 1930
        - Typescript (Folder 60: 16-21)
        - Evaluations for publication (Folder 60: 22)
        - Publication contract (Folder 60: 23)
      - "U istochnika," 1939. (Folder 60: 24)
      - "Deus ex machina," 1940. (Folder 60: 25)
      - My obviniaem, 1942. (Box-folder 61: 1)
      - "Po ukhabam zhizni" (memoirs re his arrest), 1950's. (Folder 61: 2)
      - "Shagi zhizni: Roman-khronika"
        - Typescript, n.d. (Folder 61: 3-5)
        - Review by Ts. Dmitrieva, 1955. (Folder 61: 6)
- EVDOKIIA TORKHOVA-SINIAVSKAIA FILE, 1855-1955
  - Biographical file
    - Birth certificate, 1886. (Folder 61: 7)
      Also includes birth and marriage certificates of her parents Ivan Torkhov and Evdokiia Repkina, 1855, 1872
    - Diplomas and certificates of education, 1898-1912., See also OVERSIZE FILE/Award (Folder 61: 8)
      Includes "Pokhval'nyii List," 1900.
    - Work register (Trudovoi Spisok), 1926-1929 (Folder 61: 9)
    - Identity card and membership books, 1927-1931 (Folder 61: 10)
    - Papers related to Torkhov family village property, 1927, 1932 (Folder 61: 11)
    - Autobiography, 1932. (Folder 61: 12)
    - Death certificate, 1955 (Folder 61: 13)
  - Correspondence
    - Litvinenko, Hieromonk Ioanikii (Mt. Athos), 1893 (Folder 61: 14)
    - Siniavskii, Andrei, 1951-1954. (Folder 61: 15)
      Also includes letters of Viva Siniavskaia
  - Diaries.
    Holograph notebooks with inserts of childhood drawings, writings, and photographs of Andrei Siniavskii
    - General, 1937-1938. (Folder 61: 16-17)
      Includes school notebook compiled for Pushkin Centennial, 1937
    - Nos. 1, 1925-1928 (Folder 61: 18)
    - Nos. 2, 1929-1932 January (Folder 61: 19)
    - Nos. 3, 1932 January - 1933 October (Box-folder 62: 1)
    - Nos. 4, 1933 November - 1933 September (Folder 62: 2)
    - Nos. 5, 1933 October - 1939 January (Folder 62: 3)
    - Nos. 6, 1939 January - 1941 June (Folder 62: 4)
    - Nos. 7, 1941 June - 1947 July (Folder 62: 5)
- MARIIA ROZANOVA FILE, 1966-1999
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - General, 1974-1996 (Folder 62: 6-7)
      - Replies to letters received, 1981-1986 (Folder 62: 8)
    - Gastev, Iurii, 1980-1996 (Folder 62: 9)
    - Golomshtok, Igor', 1984-1986 (Folder 62: 10)
    - Ianov, Aleksandr and Lydia, 1980-1983 (Folder 62: 11)
    - Laqueur, Walter, 1985-1988 (Folder 62: 12)
    - Lenchik, Lev, 1987-1993 (Folder 62: 13)
    - Litvinov, Pavel and Maya, 1979 (Folder 62: 14)
    - Rapetti, Sergio, 1982-1990 (Folder 62: 15)
    - Schweitzer, Victoria, 1980-1987 (Folder 62: 16)
    - Taratov, Aleksandr, 1994-1995 (Folder 62: 17)
  - Interview, n.d. (Folder 62: 18)
  - Memorabilia. Chocolate wrapper passed to Andrei Siniavskii in prison, 1966 (Folder 62: 19)
  - Writings. (Folder 62: 20)
    Includes "Zatmil li solntse Solzhenitsyn?," n.d. Typescript
- SINTAKSIS FILE, 1968-1995 (Box 63)
  - General. Open letter of editors to supporters, n.d. (Folder 63: 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1974-1996 (Folder 63: 2-3)
    - Adamatskii, Igor, 1989 (Folder 63: 4)
    - Aigi, Gennadii, 1982-1984 (Folder 63: 5)
    - Alloi, Vladimir, open letter to F. Burlatskii, 1990 (Folder 63: 6)
    - Andreev, Vadim, 1973 (Folder 63: 7)
    - Belotserkovskii, Vadim, 1976-1986., See also SUBJECT FILE/Mijailov, Mijailo (Folder 63: 8)
    - Bobyshev, Dmitrii, 1987 (Folder 63: 9)
    - Deutsche Welle, 1981 (Folder 63: 10)
    - Dobrodeev, Dmitrii, 1989 (Folder 63: 11)
    - Donde, Aleksandr, 1985 (Folder 63: 12)
    - Efimov, Igor, 1989 (Folder 63: 13)
    - Fel'dman, Aleksandr, 1986 (Folder 63: 14)
    - Genis, Aleksandr, 1985-1989 (Folder 63: 15)
    - Il'ina, E., 1980 (Folder 63: 16)
    - Kharitonov, Mark, 1990 (Folder 63: 17)
    - Kontakt (Jerzy Torgolski), 1984 (Folder 63: 18)
    - Kuraev, Mikhail, 1989-1990 (Folder 63: 19)
    - Kuternitskii, Andrei, 1991 (Folder 63: 20)
    - Levitin-Krasnov, Anatolii, 1983-1991 (Folder 63: 21)
    - Limonov, Eduard, 1980 (Folder 63: 22)
    - Linetskii, Vadim, 1989-1993 (Folder 63: 23)
    - Lyriker Treffen Münster, 1987 (Folder 63: 24)
    - Mal'tsev, Iurii, 1985 (Folder 63: 25)
    - Mnatsakanova (Netzkowa), Elena, 1981-1983 (Folder 63: 26)
    - Nazarov, Andrei, 1985 (Folder 63: 27)
    - Novikov, V., 1992 (Folder 63: 28)
    - Petrov, Nikolai, 1987-1988 (Folder 63: 29)
    - Pomerants, Grigorii, 1991 (Folder 63: 30)
    - Poznanskii, Aleksandr, 1986 (Folder 63: 31)
    - Reiman, Mikhail, 1981-1983 (Folder 63: 32)
    - Rogovskii, M., 1989 (Folder 63: 33)
    - Rudich, V., n.d. (Folder 63: 34)
    - Russica Publishers, Inc. and Russica Book and Art, Inc., 1981-1986 (Folder 63: 35)
    - Savitskii, Dmitrii, 1986 (Folder 63: 36)
    - Schweitzer, Viktoria, 1981-1987 (Folder 63: 37)
    - Shrayer-Petrov, D., 1990 (Folder 63: 38)
    - Shtromas, Alexander, 1981-1982. (Folder 63: 39)
      Includes correspondence between Alexander Shtromas and Grigorii Pomerants
    - Sokolov, Valentin, 1989 (Folder 63: 40)
    - Sukonik, Aleksandr, 1986 (Folder 63: 41)
    - Temin, Gennadii, 1989-1990. (Box-folder 64: 1)
      Includes Andrei Siniavskii's replies
    - Temkina, Marina, 1986-1990 (Folder 64: 2)
    - Tolstaia, Tatiana, 1989 (Folder 64: 3)
    - Tolstoy, Ivan (Les Editions Grjebine), 1992 (Folder 64: 4)
    - Uniwersitet Jagiellonski, 1991 (Folder 64: 5)
    - Vail, Petr., See Genis, Aleksandr
    - Vishnevskaia, Iuliia, 1993 (Folder 64: 6)
    - Vishniak, V., 1985 (Folder 64: 7)
    - Zaslavskii, Victor, 1985 (Folder 64: 8)
    - Zinik, Zinovii, 1983-1990 (Folder 64: 9)
  - Manuscripts submitted for publication. Arranged alphabetically by name of author.
    Also includes printed copies of works by authors submitting manuscripts
    - General, 1971-1996
      - Author unknown (Folder 64: 10-13)
      - Author unknown (Box-folder 65: 1-7)
      - A (Box-folder 66: 1-3)
      - B (Folder 66: 4-7)
      - B (Box-folder 67: 1-3)
      - C (Folder 67: 4-7)
      - D (Box-folder 68: 1-2)
      - E (Folder 68: 3)
      - F (Folder 68: 4)
      - G (Folder 68: 5-7)
      - G (Box-folder 69: 1-7)
      - Ia (Box-folder 70: 1-3)
      - I (Folder 70: 4-5)
      - K (Folder 70: 6-8)
      - K (Box-folder 71: 1-6)
      - L (Box-folder 72: 1-4)
      - M (Folder 72: 5)
      - M (Box-folder 73: 1-3)
      - N (Folder 73: 4)
      - O (Folder 73: 5)
      - P (Box-folder 74: 1-6)
      - R (Box-folder 75: 1-5)
      - Sh (Folder 75: 6)
      - S (Folder 75: 7)
      - S (Box-folder 76: 1-9)
      - Ts (Box-folder 77: 1)
      - T (Folder 77: 2-3)
      - U (Folder 77: 4-5)
      - V (Folder 77: 6-9)
      - V (Box-folder 78: 1)
      - Z (Folder 78: 2-6)
    - Abovin-Egides, Petr, "Est' li v Russkoi Mysli mysl'?," 1990. (Box-folder 79: 1)
    - Adamatskii, Igor.
      Typescripts
      - "Uteshitel'," n.d. (Folder 79: 2)
      - "Cherdak," 1977 (Folder 79: 3)
      - "Pritchudy," 1987 (Folder 79: 4)
    - Agafonov, Vasilii, short stories, n.d. (Folder 79: 5)
    - Aigi, Gennadii., See also PHOTOGRAPHS/Aigi, Gennadii
      - "Son i poeziia," 1982. (Folder 79: 6)
      - "Tetradi Veroniki," 1983. (Folder 79: 7)
      - Polia-dvoiniki, 1987. (Folder 79: 8)
    - Akhmet'ev, Ivan, poetry, n.d. (Box-folder 80: 1)
    - Alliluyeva, Svetlana.
      - "Kniga dlia vnuchek," n.d. (Folder 80: 2)
      - Translation of Krishnamurti, 1988 (Folder 80: 3-5)
    - Altunian, Aleksandr, essays, n.d. (Folder 80: 6)
      Typescripts. Includes letter from Larisa Bogoraz
    - Amusin, Mark, "Evropeiskie sny...," n.d. (Folder 80: 7)
    - Andreev, Daniil
      - Biography, 1967. (Folder 80: 8)
      - Review by Grigorii Pomerants, "Tiuremnaia lirika Daniila Andreeva," n.d. (Folder 80: 9)
      - Writing, "Russkie bogi," n.d. (Folder 80: 10-12)
    - Andreev, Vadim, "Na rubezhe," 1976. (Folder 80: 13)
    - Antonov, Sergei, short stories, n.d. (Folder 80: 14-15)
    - Arabov, Iurii, "Vivat novye vremena!," n.d. (Box-folder 81: 1)
    - Auerbach, Elizaveta, memoirs re Koktebel and miscellany, n.d. (Folder 81: 2)
    - Babenyshev, A., "Ne roi drugomu mogilu," n.d. (Folder 81: 3)
    - Bakhrakh, Aleksandr, "Pis'ma Mariny Tsvetaevoi," n.d. (Folder 81: 4)
    - Bartov, Arkadii, "Progukli s Mukhinym," n.d. (Folder 81: 5)
    - Batchev, Vladimir, poetry, n.d. (Folder 81: 6)
    - Belotserkovskii, Vadim., See SUBJECT FILE/Belotserkovskii, Vadim
    - Berezov, Nikolai, "Moia zhizn'," n.d. (Folder 81: 7-9)
    - Bitov, Andrei, "Pamiatnik zaitsu," 1985. (Box-folder 82: 1)
    - Bobyshev, Dimitrii.
      - General, 1985 (Folder 82: 2)
      - "Polnota vsego," 1980 (Folder 82: 3)
    - Boitsov, Aleksandr, "Pravoslavnaia 'ideologiia'i 'sotsiologicheskii vybor'," n.d. (Folder 82: 4)
    - Bol'shakov, Vladimir, "Opastnost' chuzhoi krovi," chap. 6, n.d. (Folder 82: 5)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, speech at Boston University, 1988. (Folder 82: 6)
    - Burtin, Iurii, "Gorbachev," 1992. (Folder 82: 7)
    - Chalidze, Valerii, "Ifigeniia," n.d. (Folder 82: 8)
    - Chigrin, Evgenii, "Introduktsiia sentiabria," n.d. (Folder 82: 9)